gearank.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy | Gearank

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site or enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

• To personalize user's experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.  
• To improve our website in order to better serve you.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. 

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**  
• Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

**If users disable cookies in their browser:**

If you disable cookies some features will be disabled. It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly, specifically:  
• Automatic login upon revisiting

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

**Third party links**

At our discretion we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. <https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en>

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

**We have implemented the following:**  
• Google Display Network Impression Reporting  
• Demographics and Interests Reporting  
• DoubleClick Platform Integration

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

Opting out:  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the [Network Advertising initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**Amazon**

Gearank.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com and other Amazon stores worldwide. Amazon may also set cookies when you click on advertising links to visit their websites.

**Sweetwater**

[Sweetwater](https://www.sweetwater.com/) supports Gearank.com with advertising which may be served from this website or via Google, including Remarketing Ads, and may result in third party cookies being set on this website and when you click advertising links to visit the Sweetwater website. We do not share any personal information you provide to us with Sweetwater. Although there are many advertising links to Sweetwater on this website, Sweetwater does not have any editorial role in the content or product recommendations that we provide.

**Hotjar**

Gearank uses software called Hotjar. Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd. The personal data collected by Hotjar includes Cookies, Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in their [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy).

Hotjar honors generic "Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell Hotjar's script not to collect any of the User's data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Please see Hotjar’s [Opt-Out Information](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out) for further details.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. - See more at: [http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/...](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf)

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**  
Users can visit our site anonymously  
We have added a link to our privacy policy on our home page.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:  
• On our Privacy Policy Page  
Users are able to change their personal information:  
• By logging in to their account

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

PO Box 138  
Mount Nebo, QLD 4520  
Australia  
Contact Form  
\+ 61 7 3862 3346

Last Edited on 2019-06-18.
